oecdbetterlifeindex.org 2011-11-26

# Privacy Policy – OECD Better Life Index

## Privacy Protection

This policy establishes how we handle the information we learn about you when you visit the main OECD website ([www.oecd.org](http://www.oecd.org/)), any of its satellite website(s) or any of their pages (collectively “the OECD website(s)”). Protecting the privacy and personal data of our visitors is of utmost importance to us. Protecting your privacy and your personal data is an important aspect of the way we create, organise and implement our activities on-line and off-line. The OECD website(s) follow(s) the principles set out in the Recommendation of the Council concerning Guidelines Governing the Protection of Privacy and Transborder Flows of Personal Data (C(80)58/FINAL).

Return to top

## Linkages Characteristics

The specific practices outlined in this privacy statement apply to the OECD website(s), notably the OECDiLibrary ([www.OECD-iLibrary.org](http://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/)) and the OECD Online Bookshop ([www.oecd.org/bookshop](http://www.oecd.org/bookshop)). Other bodies/entities (such as, but not limited to, NEA, IEA, ITF, FATF, etc.) linked to the OECD may have slightly different practices, though the commitment to your privacy will always be the same. You are encouraged to review the privacy statements of other bodies/entities when visiting their websites. Our website(s) may include links to third party Web server(s) for online payments.

Return to top

## Purpose Specifications and Data Collection

In general, you can browse the OECD website(s) without disclosing any information about yourself. If you visit the OECD website(s) to read or download information, we collect and store only the following information that is automatically recognised: the date and time, the originating IP address, the domain name, the type of browser and operating system used (if provided by the browser), the URL of the referring page (if provided by the browser), the object requested and the completion status of the request. For more details on these data and the reason why we log them, please see Information automatically recognised and logged.

Return to top

## Cookies and Other Technologies

As described above, we sometimes collect anonymous information from visits to our website(s) to help us provide better customer service. For example, we keep track of the domains from which people visit and we also measure visitor activity on the OECD website(s), but we do so in ways that keep the information anonymous. We use the information that we collect to measure the number of visitors to the different areas of our website(s), and to help us make our website(s) more useful to visitors. This includes analysing these logs periodically to measure the traffic through our servers, the number of pages visited and the level of demand for pages and topics of interest. The logs may be preserved indefinitely and used at any time and in any way to prevent security breaches and to ensure the integrity of the data on our servers.

We collect the anonymous information we mentioned above through the use of various technologies, one of which is called “cookies”. A cookie is an element of data that a website can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your hard drive. For example, OECD.Stat and the iLibrary record whether you are using the English or French interface so whenever you visit these sites, you are taken to the language you prefer. Other session information (marked lists, search terms) is recorded with an expiration date. On the OECD Online Bookshop and “MyOECD” (if users register for it), cookies are used to save the visitor’s password so that it does not have to be re-entered at each new visit. The following information is stored in the cookies:

  * IP address
  * Session number 
  * Customer ID (first name, last name, job function)
  * Identification number for online payments, when used.
  * If the user has chosen “remember login and password”, those two items are encoded and added to the cookie.
  * If a “registered” user to MyOECD returns to the site without logging in, the ID stored in the cookie are used to track the user (unless the user manually deleted the cookie, at which point the server will automatically regenerate another cookie).

Also, when we collect personal data from you in connection with a transaction we may extract some information about that transaction in an anonymous format and combine it with other anonymous information.

This anonymous information is used and analysed only at an aggregate level to help us understand trends and patters. None of this information is reviewed at an individual level. If you do not want your transaction details used in this manner, you can either disable your cookies or opt-out at the order or request stage.

We collect the personal data that you volunteer on registration for “MyOECD”, order, survey, competition, or other forms, or by e-mail. For more details on these data and the reason why we process them, see Other personal data volunteered and processed.

We do not associate the information stored in a visitor’s cookie with any other personal data about that visitor.

All our employees and processors who have access to personal data and are associated with the processing of that data are obliged to respect the confidentiality of data.

Return to top

## Visitor’s Choice

Registering on our website(s) is optional. If you choose not to register or provide personal information, you can still use the OECD website(s). However, you will not be able to purchase items or receive e-mail alerts. The OECD views the customer information that it collects as a valuable and confidential asset of which we take great care to ensure its safety.

You may choose to register on “MyOECD” or on the OECDiLibrary and receive promotional or marketing information from the OECD or its centres by selecting the appropriate option when you register personal data. If you choose to register, your information will be available to OECD Staff and to delegations for the purpose of events management. If you do not wish to continue receiving promotional or marketing information, please notify us by e-mail at [oecddirect@oecd.org](mailto:oecddirect@oecd.org) or [oecdilibrary@oecd.org](mailto:oecdilibrary@oecd.org).

Return to top

## Disclosure

You may also choose to receive promotional or marketing information from other organisations. You can indicate this choice by selecting the appropriate option during registration. When you choose to receive promotional or marketing information from other organisations, we only disclose your name and address to them. However, you should note that other organisations may follow privacy practices which are different from our own privacy practices. At any time you can ask us not to further disclose your name and address by sending an e-mail to [webmaster@oecd.org](mailto:webmaster@oecd.org).

Return to top

## Individual Participation / Access

You can ask us whether we are keeping personal data about you, and you can also request to receive a copy of that personal data. Before sending you any personal data, we will ask you to provide proof of your identity. If you are not able to provide proof of your identity, we reserve the right to refuse to send you the personal data.

We will make a sincere effort to respond in a timely manner to your requests to the previous questions or to correct inaccuracies in your personal information. At any time, you may request that we delete or correct your personal information in our logs. For such requests, please contact [webmaster@oecd.org](mailto:webmaster@oecd.org).

Return to top

## Security

We intend to protect the quality and integrity of your personal information. The OECD has implemented technologies and security policies to protect the stored personal data of our users from unauthorised access, improper use, alteration, unlawful or accidental destruction and accidental loss. We will continue to enhance our security procedures, as new technology becomes available. OECD employees and processors who have access to personal data are obliged to respect the privacy of our visitors and the confidentiality of their personal data.

Return to top

## Personalised URL

With the “MyOECD” function, the OECD provides a personalised URL (link) that brings the visitor to a personalised Web page. Such a personal URL is readily identifiable and by clicking on that link and going to a personal Web page you are agreeing to let OECD collect information about your session visits. We use this information to help us provide you with information that matches your interests. If you do not wish information to be used in this way, simply do not click on the “MyOECD” option.

Return to top

## Links

Throughout the OECD website(s), you will find links to third party websites. For example, our Online Bookshop website includes a link to a third party Web server for online payments. Please note that the OECD is not responsible for the privacy policies or content on third party sites.

The OECD website enables you to communicate with other visitors and to post information accessible by others. You should be aware that when you use these services, your data may be collected by other visitors.

Return to top

## Notifications of Changes

As the OECD creates new services that may generate a need to amend this privacy statement, the OECD will highlight such changes on the OECD website home page. You will also find available the Previous Privacy policy statement.

Return to top

## Dispensation from prior authorisation granted by the Secretary-General

In accordance with Article 13 of the Decision of the Secretary-General on the Principles Governing Computerised Personal Data Processing (Annex XII to the Regulations, Rules and Instructions Applicable to Officials of the Organisation), please consult the derogations granted so far.

Return to top

## Privacy Support

If you have any inquiries about our privacy statement, please contact:

**OECD**  
2 rue André Pascal  
75775 PARIS Cedex 16  
E-mail: [webmaster@oecd.org](mailto:webmaster@oecd.org)  
URL: [www.oecd.org/sti/privacygenerator](http://www.oecd.org/sti/privacygenerator)

Return to top
